翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
As our last program of the day, let's talk about defining functions in Java.
今天最后一个程序讨论如何在 Java 中定义函数
So again, I'm going to use Python as the simple example.
我们再次使用 Python 作为简单的示例
I'm going to say over here, let's define a function called larger.
定义一个叫做 larger 的函数
And what it's going to do is take two variables, x and y.
它提取两个变量 x 和 y
And if x happens to be bigger than y, we'll return x.
如果 x > y 则返回 x
Otherwise, we'll return y.
否则返回 y
That's it.
写好了
And then we might say, let's print the larger of negative 5 and 10 and hopefully we get 10.
加入要打印-5和10中较大的，应该得到10
So what should the Java version of this look like?
相应的 Java 版本应该是什么样子呢？
There we go.
让我们开始吧
The larger version-- sorry, the Java version of this should look like well, we'll make a class called Large Demo.
Java 版本应该是这样的，我们创建一个名为 LargeDemo 的类
And then if we want to define a function,
如果我们想定义一个函数
we can't put it up here.
我们不能把它放在这里
If we try to define a function up here,
如果我们试图在这里定义一个函数
like define Larger or whatever, that would not work.
比如定义 larger 或别的什么，那是行不通的
In Java, all code must be part of a class.
在 Java 中，所有代码都必须是类的一部分
So I'm actually going to do the function definition here.
所以我实际上要在这里做函数定义
Now the special phrase I'm going to use, instead of Def,
不是 def，我要使用特殊的短语
in Java I'm going to say public static.
Java 中使用 public static
And then I'm going to make a function name call Larger on x, y.
函数名是 larger，参数是 x 和 y
Then I might say something like if x is bigger than y, return x, otherwise return a y.
如果 x > y 返回 x，否则返回 y
Now if I try compiling this, since Java is a statically typed language, it yells at me.
现在运行代码会报错，因为 Java 是静态语言
It says you need to tell me what x is, what y is,
需要说明 x 是什么，y是什么
and indeed what Larger is supposed to return.
以及 larger 该返回什么
So I need to say x has a type, y has a type.
所以需要写 x 有一种类型，y 有一种类型
Let's say they're integers.
假设它们是整型
And then Larger itself needs a type, which we'll put right here, right before the name of the function.
larger 本身也需要一个类型，我们将把它放在函数名之前
So now that I've written this, this is the proper program that contains the function Larger.
现在这段就是包含了 larger 函数的正确代码
And then the call to the function we'll put in the main method.
接下来在 main 方法中调用
So this is what actually gets run when we run the program.
这是当前程序运行的内容
So if we want to actually get Larger to run,
我们调用 larger 运行
we need to do something like this.
我们需要这样做
So now I run this and I get 10.
现在运行程序，得到10
So these are the equivalent programs in Python and Java.
这就是用 Python 和 Java 编写的等效程序
So some notes here, to define a function in Java--
做一些笔记，要在 Java 中定义函数...
actually we'll do one, functions must be part of a class
第一点应该是这个， 函数必须是类的一部分
as unlike Python or other languages,
与 Python 或其他语言不同
this is not part of any class.
这不是任何类的一部分
It's just a function that exists.
这只是一个函数
But here functions must be declared as part of a class in Java.
但是 Java 中函数必须定义为类的一部分
And as a quick aside, a function that is part of a class is called a method.
另外，作为类的一部分的函数称为方法
So in Java, all functions are methods.
所以 Java 中所有的函数都是方法
And this is just some programming language terminology that's pretty common.
这只是常见的编程术语
To define a function in Java, we use public static.
要在 Java 中定义函数，需要使用 public static
We will see alternate ways of defining functions later.
稍后会看到定义函数的另一种方法
So they're not always public static.
也就是说不一定非要使用 public static
This isn't quite the same thing as Def, but for our purposes today it basically is.
它与 def 不完全相同，但暂时我们认为它们基本一样
Next we have, all parameters of a function must have a declared type,
接下来，函数的所有参数类型都必须定义
and the return value of the function must have a declared type.
函数的返回值类型也必须定义
So here our declared type is Int.
这里我们定义的类型是整型
So for example, we try to say like, string x equals larger minus 5, 10, we would get a compiler error.
假如我们这样写，String x = larger(-5, 10)，编译器会报错
Larger is a function returns Ints.
larger 函数返回整型
This is a string variable.
这是一个字符串
And maybe I guess I'll mention just as an aside,
或许我应该单独记下来
functions in Java return only one value.
Java 中的函数只返回一个值
So I can't say like, Int, string,
所以我不能写 int，String
and then have two things come out of Larger.
让 larger 返回两个东西
That's not allowed in Java.
这在 Java 中是不允许的
You get one thing.
只能返回一个
So that's basically the idea behind how we define functions in Java.
这基本上就是 Java 定义函数的思想
And that's it for programming for today.
以上就是今天的程序
Now, I don't expect that me, having done all these demos,
现在你们完成这些演示，不再依赖我
that you could just walk right out there
你可以直接走出去
and write a bunch of programs, you could write functions, because like anything it takes practice.
去写一堆程序，你可以写函数，因为这需要练习
So there are labs that go with this set of videos.
有一些视频的配套实验
There is a book.
有一本书
And I encourage you to experiment with those in order to gain a deeper understanding.
我鼓励你们实验来加深理解
But we're not quite done yet.
但其实还没完呢
So I want to make some observations about the code I've written.
观察我所写的代码
You'll notice that throughout the code,
你会注意到在整个代码中
well there's not much here, but we've named things in a way that makes the code self readable.
虽然内容不多，但是我们的命名使代码易读
What does this class do?
这节课讲了什么？
Well, it's a demo of the Larger function.
讲了 larger 函数的示例
What does this function do?
这个函数功能是什么？
Well, it's called Larger.
它叫 larger
We didn't call it F. I mean, we could have called it F.
我们没有叫它 F，虽然我们可以这么叫
Also work just the same, but the code as written here is more descriptive.
效果一样，但我写的代码更好理解
So one of the very important things we're going to teach you in this class,
所以这门课要教你们一件非常重要的事情是
or hope to because we're not going to manually examine your code so I guess you could get away with it, trick us.
你可以投机取巧，因为我们不会手动检查代码
But what I think you should really strive for, even though we're not watching right over your shoulder,
但我认为你应该自觉，即便我没有在背后盯着你
is to write code that is going to be self-documenting, that's readable.
那就是保证代码可读性
Above all else, you should write code that if someone looks at it, they can understand it.
其他人看到你的代码就能理解
There are plenty of other ways that you could write this code.
有很多方法编写这段代码
But this way, I think, is one of the very clearest.
但这是最清晰的方式之一
One other little thing I'll mention is that well, right here I've been showing you comments.
另一件小事是，其实我已经展示过了
Obviously in your code you're not going to have a big paragraph at the end explaining all the things you observed writing it.
你可能不会在代码末尾写一大段文字解释所有代码
Instead, what you'll want to do is make sure that where you do use comments,
你要知道在哪里写注释
it's there so that someone else can understand your code.
让其他人更好地理解你的代码
So I'd say there's not really much to comment in this program
这段程序其实没什么可注释的
except that there's a general rule of thumb that when you write a function,
除了一个写函数时的普遍规则
it's nice to put a little comment at the top describing what it does.
最好在顶部添加一点注释来描述功能
So in Python it might look something like this,
Python 中是这样的
returns the larger of x and y in these triple quotes.
引号中写：“返回 x 和 y 中较大者”
In Java, the common convention is to do slash star star, so an extra star here for our block comment, and write a description--
Java 的注释一般是斜线、星号、星号，还有一个星号在末尾
returns the larger of x and y.
返回 x 和 y 中较大者
Now in this case, it's a little silly.
给这段代码写注释有点傻
But there are tools that exist that will take source code,
但有些工具可以处理源代码
find all of the slash star star comments,
找到所有点注释
and generate a nice HTML document.
生成一个漂亮的 HTML 文档
And so for that reason you're encouraged to always use Java dot comments,
因此我们鼓励你始终使用 Java 点注释
even whenever a function is pretty self-explanatory.
即使函数不言自明
Now the java doc format, sometimes people also add little tags here.
Java doc 格式也支持一些小标签
So you can add--
比如你可以加@
there's various conventions, but you can write things like pre-condition
这有很多约定，但一般写一些前置条件
and explain the thing you expect to be true for the function, whatever.
或解释函数期待的返回值之类的
There's a whole different set of ideas about what kind of tags you can have.
你可以使用哪些标签不是确定的
We're not going to typically require those in this class.
我们通常不会要求这个班级的学生
But do be aware they exist.
但一定要意识到它们的存在
It is also pretty common to write a Java doc string at the beginning,
在开头编写 Java doc 也很常见
something like demonstrates creation of a larger method or creation of a method in Java.
比如：“在 Java 中创建 larger 方法示例”
Something like that.
差不多吧
I mean, this is kind of weird meta thing,
这件事可能有点奇怪
since it's actually just for instruction.
它其实就是为了引导
So you might have Java docs at the top.
所以你可能在顶部写 Java doc
For this case, I don't know, maybe not.
这种情况可能不用写
But yeah, so be aware this is a good practice.
但是你要知道这是个例子
But the most important thing is not the minor details of the tags or the slash star stars.
标签和点注释的细节不重要
It's really, you should be striving to make sure your code is readable to other people.
重要的是你要保证代码对其他人易读
And sometimes you'll find that those other people are actually you.
有时候你会发现那些人其实就是你自己
What do I mean by that?
什么意思呢？
Well, you wrote a program in September of 2014,
比如你在2014年9月写了一个程序
and then May of 2018 rolls around and you need to fix it.
然后2018年5月需要修复它
It is a great favor to yourself in the future to write code that is understandable.
编写通俗易懂的代码将有很大的帮助
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）